Get ready to jam.
Space Jam is a comedy, animation, family film directed by Joe Pytka.
With their freedom on the line, the Looney Tunes seek the help of NBA superstar
Michael Jordan to win a basketball game against a team of moronic aliens.
Michael Jordan, played by Michael Jordan.
Stan Podolak, played by Wayne Knight.
Juanita Jordan, played by Theresa Randle.
Jeffery Jordan, played by Manner Washington.
Marcus Jordan, played by Eric Gordon.
Jasmine Jordan, played by Penny Bae Bridges.
Space Jam is a 1996 American live-action animated sports comedy film directed by Joe Pytka and
written by Leo Benvenuti, Steve Rudnick, Timothy Harris, and Herschel Weingrod.
The first film produced by Warner Bros.
Feature Animation, it stars basketball player Michael Jordan as himself; the live-action cast also includes
Wayne Knight and Theresa Randle while Billy West and Danny DeVito headline the voice cast.
The film follows Jordan as he is brought out of retirement by the Looney Tunes characters to help them win a
basketball match against invading aliens intent on enslaving them as amusement park attractions.
Space Jam premiered in Los Angeles on November 10, 1996, and was released
theatrically in the United States on November 15, by Warner Bros.
under its Family Entertainment label.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who were divided over its premise of combining Jordan and his profession with the
Looney Tunes characters, while the technical achievements of its intertwining of live-action and animation were praised.
It was a commercial success, grossing $250.2 million worldwide against an $80 million budget, becoming the
highest-grossing basketball film of all time until 2022, and the tenth-highest-grossing film of 1996.
A standalone sequel, Space Jam: A New Legacy, was released
in 2021, with LeBron James in the lead role.
The sequel received generally negative reviews and failed to
match the commercial success of the first film.
The film explores themes of sports, cartoon,
villain, basketball, slapstick comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.